Guide to the Georgia O'Keeffe Foundation Records
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence Files, circa 1950-2006; Series I; 65; (52 boxes)
  - Abiquiu Office Files
    - Individuals, organizations, and subjects
      - Garden plots (Box 15)
      - Garwood, Susan (Box 15)
      - Ghost Ranch, 3 (Box 15)
      - Gihon Foundation (Box 15)
      - Girard Foundation (Box 15)
      - Grad, Bonnie (Box 15)
      - Grantmakers in the Arts (Box 15)
      - Graphique de France, 3 (Box 15)
      - Greenough, Sarah (Box 15)
      - Hallmark Cards, Inc. (Box 15)
      - Hanford, Warren (Box 15)
      - Harcourt Brace Jovanovich, Inc. (Box 15)
      - Harding, Mangus (Mike) (Box 15)
        Contains photocopies of letters to Georgia O'Keeffe dated from 1940 through 1972
      - Harry N. Abrams, Inc., 2 (Box 16)
      - Harwood Foundation (Box 16)
      - Heitzeg, Steve (Box 16)
      - Helms, Anne Adams (Box 16)
      - Henn, Harry (Box 16)
      - Henry Luce Foundation, Inc. (Box 16)
      - Heritage Resource (Box 16)
      - Herz, Cary (Box 16)
      - Historic American Buildings Survey (HABS) (Box 16)
      - Historic Los Luceros (Box 16)
      - Hogrefe, Jeff (Box 16)
      - Homer, William I. (Box 16)
      - House Tours (Box 16)
      - Hunt, Helen (Box 16)
      - Ingham, Carol (Box 16)
      - Jacobson, Robin (Box 16)
      - Janssen, Stéphane (Box 16)
      - Japan (Box 16)
      - Japan Broadcasting Corporation (Box 16)
      - Joe Ferran Community Center (Box 16)
      - Johnson, Ruth Carter (Box 16)
        Contains photocopies of letters to Georgia O'Keeffe dating from 1964 through 1968
      - Jones, Everett (Box 16)
      - Karsh, Yousef (Box 16)
      - Keck, Caroline K., 3 (Box 16)
        Contains photocopies of correspondence dating from 1946 to 1981, between paintings conservator Caroline Keck and O'Keeffe, Doris Bry, and others, concerning O'Keeffe's paintings.
      - Kemper, Crosby (Box 16)
      - Kimball, Clark (Box 16)
      - Kunin, Myron (Box 16)
      - Klein, Calvin (Box 16)
      - Kronkright Center for Cultural Materials (Box 16)
      - Kusama, Yayoi (Box 16)
      - Lamport, Anthony (Box 16)
      - Landau, Emily Fisher, 2 (Box 16)
      - Landmark General Corporation (Box 16)
      - Landscape Museum, 2 (Box 16)
      - Lannan Foundation (Box 16)
      - Lectures (Box 16)
      - Lescher & Lescher, Ltd. (Box 16)
      - Letterhead (Box 16)
      - Levitt, Arthur (Box 16)
      - Library of Congress (Box 16)
      - Lost art (Box 16)
      - Louisa Stude Sarofim Foundation (Box 16)
      - Lowe, Sue Davidson (Box 16)
      - Lukens, Cynthia (Box 16)
      - Luna Imaging, Inc., 2 (Box 16)
      - Lunn, Harry H. (Box 16)
      - Lynes, Barbara Buhler (Box 16)
      - McCabe, Connie (Box 16)
      - McCracken, Melissa (Box 16)
      - McCurdy School (Box 16)
      - McDermott, Mrs. Eugene (Box 16)
      - Mailing list (Box 16)
      - Maintenance and construction (Box 16)
      - Maroney, James (Box 16)
      - Marcus, Stanley (Box 16)
      - Mason, Marsha (Box 16)
      - Memos from Georgia Smith (Box 16)
      - Memos from Liz Glassman, 2 (Box 16)
      - Memos from Sarah Burt (Box 16)
      - Memos to Pita (Box 16)
      - Memos to staff (Box 16)
      - Mercedes-Benz (Box 17)
      - Merrill, Carol S. (Box 17)
      - Messinger, Lisa Mintz (Box 17)
      - Metropolitan Home (Box 17)
      - Michishita, Kyoko (Box 17)
      - Miers, Charles (Box 17)
      - Micucci, Dana (Box 17)
      - Mitchell, Brenda (Box 17)
      - Monastery of Christ in the Desert, 2 (Box 17)
      - Morgan Manhattan Storage Co. (Box 17)
      - Moyers, Bill (Box 17)
      - National Cowgirl Hall of Fame (Box 17)
      - National Endowment for the Arts (Box 17)
      - National Endowment for the Humanities (Box 17)
      - National Geographic Society (Box 17)
      - National Park Service, 5 (Box 17)
      - National Trust for Historic Preservation in the United States, 5 (Box 17)
      - National Trust for Historic Preservation in the United States, 16 (Box 18)
      - New Mexico Community Foundation (Box 19)
      - New Mexico Magazine (Box 19)
      - Noto, Lou and Joan (Box 19)
      - O'Keeffe catalogues (Box 19)
      - O'Keeffe, Claire (Box 19)
      - O'Keeffe exhibitions (Box 19)
      - O'Keeffe family photo album (Box 19)
        Contains photocopies of photographs held in an album lent to the Georgia O'Keeffe Museum
      - O'Keeffe, Ida (Box 19)
      - O'Keeffe letters (Box 19)
        Contains photocopies of letters from O'Keeffe to Carlotta Corpron, Amelia Schmoll, James Johnson Sweeney, and Patricia Vale
      - O'Keeffe Museum (Box 19)
      - Oral history project, 4 (Box 19)
      - Peters, Sarah Whitaker, 3 (Box 19)
      - Philippe Halsman Studio (Box 19)
      - Pillow cover letter (Box 19)
      - Planet Art - CD-ROM (Box 19)
      - Policies and agreements (Box 19)
      - Poling, John D. (Box 19)
      - Pollock-Krasner Foundation, Inc. (Box 19)
      - Pomegranate Communications Inc., 2 (Box 19)
      - Porter, Eliot (Box 19)
      - Press releases, 4 (Box 19)
      - Princeton Gallery of Fine Arts (Box 19)
      - Print Council of America (Box 19)
      - Publications (Box 19)
      - Randall, Eliza (Box 19)
      - Random House Value Publishing, Inc. (Box 19)
      - Read, Howard (Box 19)
      - Recursos (Box 19)
      - Redmond, Bill (Box 19)
      - Reich, Sheldon (Box 19)
      - Reily, Nancy Hopkins, 2 (Box 19)
      - Research project (Box 19)
      - Resources (Box 19)
      - Rice Design Alliance (Box 20)
      - Rights and reproductions policy (Box 20)
      - Richardson, Bill (Box 20)
      - Rispoli, Lou (Box 20)
      - Rizzoli International Publications, 2 (Box 20)
      - Robinson, Roxana (Box 20)
      - Rose, Barbara, 2 (Box 20)
      - Saint Thomas Parish (Box 20)
      - Santa Fe Chamber Music Festival, 2 (Box 20)
      - Santa Fe Institute (Box 20)
      - Santa Fe Institute of Fine Art (Box 20)
      - Santa Fe statistics (Box 20)
      - Sarah's talk on the house (Box 20)
      - Sarkisian, Paul (Box 20)
      - Save the Jemez (Box 20)
      - Scheinbaum & Russek, Ltd. (Box 20)
      - Schirmer/Mosel Verlag, 2 (Box 20)
      - School of American Research (Box 20)
      - Schwartz, Donna and Marvin (Box 20)
      - Schwartz, Sanford (Box 20)
      - Sebring, Thomas (Box 20)
      - Sedgwick, Detert, Moran & Arnold (Box 20)
      - Shansby, Gary (Box 20)
      - Sheba (Box 20)
      - Sheldon, Huntington (Box 20)
      - Silver, Laurie (Box 20)
      - Sills, Philip (Box 20)
      - Smithsonian Institution (Box 20)
      - Sotheby's, 3 (Box 20)
      - Southwestern Bell (Box 20)
      - Speyer, Darthea (Box 20)
      - Staff meetings (Box 20)
      - Stagebill Seminar (Box 20)
      - Steuben (Box 20)
      - Stewart, Tabori & Chang (Box 20)
      - Stieglitz photograph materials (Box 20)
      - Stieglitz photograph proposals (Box 20)
      - Stinehour Press (Box 20)
      - Studio re-creation (Box 20)
      - Suazo, Jackie (Box 20)
      - Surveying (land) (Box 20)
      - Tamarind Institute (Box 20)
      - Taubman, Alfred (Box 20)
      - te Neues Publishing Company (Box 20)
      - Telepraisal (Box 20)
      - Temenos Project, Inc. (Box 20)
      - Tenth Avenue Editions, Inc., 2 (Box 20)
      - Thaw, Eugene V. (Box 21)
      - Thirteen/WNET (Box 21)
      - Thuma, Marilynn (Box 21)
      - Todtri Productions (Box 21)
      - Trademark (Box 21)
      - Transition notes (Box 21)
      - Transparencies of art, rental agreements (Box 21)
      - Tres Mowka Designs (Box 21)
      - Trujillo, Bob (Box 21)
      - Trust for Public Land (Box 21)
      - Tuckman, Phyllis (Box 21)
      - Udall, Sharyn (Box 21)
      - United States Information Agency (Box 21)
      - United States Postal Service, 2 (Box 21)
      - Universal Color Slide Company (Box 21)
      - Varon, Malcolm, 3 (Box 21)
      - Vaccaro, Tony (Box 21)
      - Visual Artists and Galleries Association, Inc. (Box 21)
      - Waintrob, Budd (Box 21)
      - Warner, Jack (Box 21)
      - Webb, Todd (Box 21)
      - Weinberg, Jane (Box 21)
      - Weinberg, Jonathan (Box 21)
      - The West (Box 21)
      - Weston, Margaret (Box 21)
      - White House: sculpture loan (Box 21)
      - Wiley, James (Box 21)
      - Wilson, MaLin (Box 21)
      - Wittgenstein, Herta (Box 21)
      - Wood, Katherine (Box 21)
      - Wood, Margaret (Box 21)
      - Wood, Myron (Box 21)
      - Woolley, J. Carrington (Box 21)
      - Yakush, Mary (Box 21)
      - Yale University Press (Box 21)
      - Yesley, Michael (Box 21)
      - Young, Anita O'Keeffe, art auction for Robert R. Young Foundation (Box 21)
      - Miscellaneous information (Box 21)
    - Applicants for foundation president, 1989-1990; 60 (Box 22)
    - Chronological files
      Arranged under two headings: Single letters, and Requests
      "Single letters" holds general correspondence, thank-you notes, and holiday cards. "Requests" contains correspondence related to permission to publish images and quotes by O'Keeffe and Alfred Stieglitz, to buy or borrow O'Keeffe and Stieglitz exhibitions and artwork, or to obtain approval of scripts for theatrical and television productions about O'Keeffe's life. The correspondence in both of these groups is related to, and at times even continued from, that found in all three of the subseries above, but it was filed in this manner by the foundation staff.
      - Single letters, 1987-1997; 12 (Box 22)
      - Single letters, 1998-2004; 18 (Box 23)
      - Requests, 1988-1990; 22 (Box 24)
      - Requests, 1991-1993; 46 (Box 25)
      - Requests, 1994-1996; 18 (Box 26)
      - Requests, 1997-1999; 28 (Box 27)
      - Requests, 1999-2000; 23 (Box 28)
      - Requests, 2001-2002; 22 (Box 29)
      - Requests, 2003-2004; 25 (Box 30)
      - Requests, 2003-2006; 10 (Box 31)
    - Faxes to and from Santa Fe office, 1992-2001 (Box 32)
    - Faxes to and from Santa Fe office, 1992-2001 (Box 33)
  - Santa Fe Office Files
    Files kept by Elizabeth Glassman; contents sometimes duplicate the material is the subseries above; file titles were assigned by foundation staff.
    - Abbeville Press (Box 34)
    - Abiquiu Real Estate (Box 34)
    - About house (Box 34)
    - About paintings (Box 34)
    - Abrams, Rebecca (Box 34)
    - Adato, Perry Miller (Box 34)
    - Adirondack Museum (Box 34)
    - After O'Keeffe (Box 34)
    - Albuquerque Museum (Box 34)
    - American Association of Museums (Box 34)
    - Annual report, 5 (Box 34)
    - Archives of American Art (Box 34)
    - Arena Stage Production (Box 34)
    - Art Dealers Association (Box 34)
    - Art Institute of Chicago (Box 34)
    - Art in Embassies Program (Box 34)
    - Art resources (Box 34)
    - Association of Historians of American Art (Box 34)
    - Auction results, 2 (Box 34)
    - Auxiliary properties (Box 34)
    - Baltimore Museum of Art (Box 34)
    - Benedikt Taschen Verlag (Box 34)
    - Birmingham Museum of Art (Box 34)
    - British Broadcasting Corporation (Box 34)
    - Bry, Doris (Box 34)
    - Bulk-rate mail (Box 34)
    - Bunnell, Peter (Box 34)
    - Calendar (Box 34)
    - Callaway Editions, Inc. (Box 34)
    - Campaign statements (Box 34)
    - "Canyon Suite" scandal (Box 34)
    - Caponigro, Eleanor (Box 34)
    - Catalog Project (Box 34)
    - Catalog Raisonné Scholars Association (Box 34)
    - Catalogs (O'Keeffe) (Box 34)
    - Chabot, Maria, 2 (Box 34)
    - Charcoal drawings (Box 34)
    - Christie's (Box 34)
    - Cleveland Museum of Art (Box 34)
    - College of Santa Fe (Box 34)
    - Colorado Springs Fine Arts Center (Box 34)
    - Colores! (Box 34)
    - Complaints (Box 34)
    - Computers research (Box 34)
    - Confidentiality (Box 34)
    - Conservation, 2 (Box 34)
    - Corbis Corporation (Box 35)
    - Corn, Wanda M. (Box 35)
    - Correspondence (miscellaneous) (Box 35)
    - Consultations: investing (Box 35)
    - Council on Foundations (Box 35)
    - Countryside Exchange (Box 35)
    - Cultural property (Box 35)
    - Dallas Museum (Box 35)
    - Davis Museum and Cultural Center (Box 35)
    - Dayton Art Institute (Box 35)
    - Database (for return) (Box 35)
    - Department of Tourism (Box 35)
    - Director's and Officers Insurance (Box 35)
    - Directors' terms history (Box 35)
    - Diverseworks (Box 35)
    - Donation cards (Box 35)
    - Earth Works (Box 35)
    - Eisler, Benito (Box 35)
    - Eldredge, Charles C. (Box 35)
    - Endowment fund (Box 35)
    - Employees, 5 (Box 35)
    - Exhibition catalogs (Box 35)
    - Exhibition requests (Box 35)
    - Fakes and forgeries (Box 35)
    - Favrot Fund (Box 35)
    - Film: "An Intimate Gallery", 2 (Box 35)
    - Fineberg, Jonathan David (Box 35)
    - Forms (Box 35)
    - Foundations
      - Artist's foundations (Box 35)
      - Brown Foundation (Box 35)
      - Girard Foundation (Box 35)
      - King Foundation (Box 35)
      - Lannan Foundation (Box 35)
      - Louisa Stude Sarofim Charitable Trust (Box 35)
      - Luce Foundation (Box 35)
      - Mabee Foundation (Box 35)
      - McDermott Foundation (Box 35)
      - Pollock-Krasner Foundation (Box 35)
      - Samuel H. Kress Foundation (Box 35)
      - Sol y Sombra Foundation (Box 35)
      - Thaw Charitable Trust (Box 35)
      - Warhol Foundation (Box 35)
      - Foundation prospects (Box 35)
    - Friends list (Box 35)
    - Funding requests (Box 35)
    - Gallup information (Box 35)
    - Gamble House (Box 35)
    - Garden Conservancy (Box 35)
    - Georgia O'Keeffe house, 3 (Box 35)
    - Ghost Ranch (Box 35)
    - Gifts and gift purchases (Box 35)
    - Glassman, Elizabeth (Box 35)
    - Grants, 2 (Box 35)
    - Hallmark Cards, Inc. (Box 35)
    - Harry N. Abrams, Inc., 2 (Box 35)
    - Harvard University Art Museums (Box 35)
    - High Museum of Art (Box 35)
    - Historic American Buildings Survey (HABS), 2 (Box 35)
    - Historic homes, 2 (Box 36)
    - Historic structures report, 2 (Box 36)
    - Holiday cards (Box 36)
    - Honolulu loan (Box 36)
    - Hotels, 2 (Box 36)
    - Humorous O'Keeffe (Box 36)
    - Information packets, 2 (Box 36)
    - Ingham property in Abiquiu (Box 36)
    - Insurance - Huntington T. Block (Box 36)
    - International visitors (Box 36)
    - Internet information (Box 36)
    - Interpretive meeting (Box 36)
    - Invitations (Box 36)
    - Jacobson, Robin (Box 36)
    - Japan (Box 36)
    - Job descriptions (Box 36)
    - Kemper Museum of Contemporary Art & Design (Box 36)
    - Kniskern, Maria (Box 36)
    - Lease: 216 McKenzie (Box 36)
    - Lee, Jamie C. (Box 36)
    - Loans, 2 (Box 36)
    - London trips (Box 36)
    - Luna Imaging (Box 36)
    - M. H. De Young Memorial Museum (Box 36)
    - Mailing list (Box 36)
    - March viewing - 1994 (Box 36)
    - May, Steven (Box 36)
    - McNay Art Museum (Box 36)
    - Mercedes-Benz (Box 36)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art (Box 36)
    - Mexico (Box 36)
    - Miscellaneous, 4 (Box 36)
    - Minneapolis Institute of Art (Box 36)
    - Modernism (Box 36)
    - Museum concept/study (Box 36)
    - Museum of Fine Arts, Boston (Box 36)
    - Museum of Fine Arts, Houston (Box 36)
    - Museum of Fine Arts (Museum of New Mexico) (Box 36)
    - National Endowment for the Arts (Box 36)
    - National Gallery of Art (U.S.), 7 (Box 36)
    - National Museum of Modern Art, Tokyo (Box 37)
    - National Museum of Women in Arts (Box 37)
    - National Park Service, 3 (Box 37)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation, 8 (Box 37)
    - Nature Conservancy (Box 37)
    - New Mexico Magazine (Box 37)
    - Newsletter (internal) (Box 37)
    - Newsletter examples (Box 37)
    - Nontaxable (Box 37)
    - Office, 2 (Box 37)
    - O'Keeffe
      - Art auctions (Box 37)
      - Home advisors (Box 37)
      - Market/sales (Box 37)
      - Museum, 6 (Box 37)
      - Notes on paintings and locations (Box 37)
      - "O'Keeffe on Paper" articles (Box 37)
      - O'Keeffe: The Poetry of Things (Box 37)
      - Works on paper, 2 (Box 37)
    - Pastels/charcoals (Box 37)
    - Pecos National Historical Park (Box 37)
    - Phillips Collection, 2 (Box 37)
    - Photos, 3 (Box 37)
    - Pikes Peak Library District photo archive grant (Box 37)
    - Policies (Box 37)
    - Pollock-Krasner House (Box 37)
    - Press, 4 (Box 37)
    - Print Council of America (Box 37)
    - Randall, Eliza (Box 37)
    - Real estate (Box 37)
    - Releases - photo permission (Box 37)
    - Reproductions, 2 (Box 37)
    - Reproductions - unauthorized (Box 37)
    - Requests, 2 (Box 37)
    - Resources (Box 37)
    - Richard York Gallery (Box 37)
    - Rizzoli International Publications, 3 (Box 38)
    - Rock crushing plant (Box 38)
    - Roswell Museum and Art Center (Box 38)
    - Royal Academy of Arts (Great Britain) (Box 38)
    - Santa Fe Chamber Music Festival (Box 38)
    - Santa Fe office lease (Box 38)
    - School of American Research (Santa Fe, N.M.) (Box 38)
    - Seminar/classes (Box 38)
    - Single museum concept (Box 38)
    - Site Santa Fe (Box 38)
    - Smithsonian Institution (Box 38)
    - Sotheby's (Box 38)
    - Southwestern Bell (Box 38)
    - Speyer, Darthea (Box 38)
    - Staatliche Kunsthalle Baden-Baden (Box 38)
    - Staff - miscellaneous (Box 38)
    - Steuben (Box 38)
    - Stieglitz, 4 (Box 38)
    - Tate Gallery (Box 38)
    - Television (Box 38)
    - Temenos Project, Inc. (Box 38)
    - Tenth Avenue Editions (Box 38)
    - "Titanic" [film] infringement (Box 38)
    - Tourism, 6 (Box 38)
    - Transparencies list (Box 38)
    - Thuma, Marilynn (Box 38)
    - United States Postal Service, 3 (Box 38)
    - University of Houston (Box 38)
    - University of New Mexico (Box 38)
    - Visual Artists and Galleries Association, Inc. (Box 38)
    - Viewshed, 2 (Box 38)
    - Wagner, Anne M. (Box 38)
    - Webb letters: Olana Gallery (Box 38)
    - Whitney Museum of American Art, 2 (Box 38)
    - Williams College Museum of Art (Box 38)
    - Willoughby Associates (Box 38)
    - Yale University Press (Box 38)
    - Y2K problem (Box 38)
    - Endowment investment proposals (Box 39)
    - Telephone message books (Box 40)
  - Catalogue Raisonné Project
    - Applications and contracts for author and research assistants, 1991-1992; 14 (Box 41)
    - Miscellaneous administrative papers, circa 1950-2000; 27 (Box 42)
      The folder "Lists" holds a circa 1950 painting inventory prepared for O'Keeffe by Doris Bry.
    - Monthly reports and correspondence, 1989-2000; 21 (Box 43)
  - O'Keeffe House Tour Records
    - Records, 1988-1996; 13 (Box 44)
    - Records, 1996-1997; 30 (Box 45)
    - Records, 1997; 15 (Box 46)
    - Records, 1997-1998; 31 (Box 47)
    - Records, 1998; 11 (Box 48)
    - Records, 1998-1999; 11 (Box 49)
    - Records, 1999; 9 (Box 50)
    - Records, 1999; 34 (Box 51)
    - Records, 1999-2005; 11 (Box 52)
- Board of Directors Files, 1986-2006; Series II; 18.75; (15 boxes)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Series II, Board of Directors Files, is restricted until March 4, 2019.
- Financial Files, 1969-2006; Series III; 25; (20 boxes)
  Series III, Financial Files, is restricted until March 4, 2029.